{"tossups": [{"question": "In one poem, this poet described unpeeling \u201cdead hands, dead stringencies.\u201d This poet began that poem with \"Stasis in darkness\" before describing themself as \"the arrow / the dew that flies.\" A third poem by this poet describes performing an action \"so it feels like hell\" and as an \"art, like everything else.\" That poem ends with this poet declaring \"I (*) rise with my red hair / And I eat men like air,\" and opens with the line \"I have done it again.\" This poet\u2019s most famous poem states \"Every woman adores a fascist\" to \"A man in black with a Meinkampf look.\" For 10 points, name this Confessional poet whose collection Ariel includes \"Lady Lazarus\" and \"Daddy.\"", "answer": "Sylvia Plath", "subcategory": "American Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "Sylvia <b><u>Plath</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Sylvia Plath", "Plath"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "NOTE TO PLAYERS: Description acceptable. In the Mahabharata, the divine fathers of Nakula and Sahadeva shared this trait. Helen and Clytemnestra also shared this trait, and another group of people with this trait were born after Zeus impregnated Leda in the form of a swan. The story of a group of people with this trait is told in the (*) Popul Vuh; those characters who defeated Seven-Macaw and the Lords of Xibalba (\"ZEE-bowel-buh\") in the ball-game were Hunahpu (\"WAH-nuh-pwuh\") and Xbalanque (\"shi-BAY-lan-kay\"). The most famous group of people that had this trait were known as the Dioscuri, or the Gemini. For 10 points, name this trait shared by Castor and Pollux, who were identical-looking siblings.", "answer": "being twins [prompt on brothers; prompt on siblings before mention]", "subcategory": "Mythology", "category": "Mythology", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>being twins</u></b> [prompt on <u>brothers</u>; prompt on <u>siblings</u> before mention]", "acceptable": ["being twins", "being twins"], "promptable": ["brothers", "siblings"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One of these surfaces, diffeomorphic to SU(2), is expressed as an embedding of lower-dimensional examples in the Hopf construction. Every simply connected closed 3-manifold is homeomorphic to one of these surfaces, a result shown by Grigori Perelman (\"gruh-GAW-ree PEH-ruhl-muhn\"). The complex analogue of the projective line is one of these surfaces named for (*) Riemann (\"REE-munh\"). The coordinate system named for these surfaces involves azimuthal and polar angles, as well as a radial distance. These surfaces consist of loci of points equidistant from a center, and the 1-dimensional example of these surfaces is a circle. For 10 points, name these boundaries of balls, whose 2-dimensional case has area 4 pi times r squared.", "answer": "n-spheres [accept 3-spheres or 2-spheres]", "subcategory": "Math", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>n-spheres</u></b> [accept <b><u>3-spheres</u></b> or <b><u>2-spheres</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["n-spheres", "n-spheres", "3-spheres", "2-spheres"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "An advocate of this cause received a call from God to \"Go to Kiowa\" (\"kai-uh-wuh\"). A riot in Portland, Maine broke out after Neal Dow\u2019s \"Maine Law\" enforced this policy in Maine. The Cullen-Harrison act weakened this policy. Frances Willard was a leader of an organization supporting this cause. Wayne Wheeler drafted a bill that would enforce this policy. The \"smashers\" and (*) hatchet-wielding Carrie Nation was a violent advocate of this policy. This policy was enforced nationwide by the Volstead Act. For 10 points, name this policy first enacted by the 18th Amendment, and repealed by the 21st, where the sale of alcohol was banned.", "answer": "prohibition [accept temperance or teetotalism; accept obvious equivalents like going dry; or descriptions like banning alcohol before mention; accept 18th Amendment before mention]", "subcategory": "American History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>prohibition</u></b> [accept <b><u>temperance</u></b> or <b><u>teetotalism</u></b>; accept <b><u>obvious equivalents like going dry</u></b>; or <b><u>descriptions like banning alcohol</u></b> before mention; accept <b><u>18th Amendment</u></b> before mention]", "acceptable": ["prohibition", "prohibition", "temperance", "teetotalism", "obvious equivalents like going dry", "descriptions like banning alcohol", "18th Amendment"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "In 2020, Shiva Ayyadurai (\"AH-yah-dure-ay\") lost a primary in this state to Kevin O'Connor. The chair of the House Ways and Means Committee, Richard Neal, represents this state\u2019s city of Holyoke. Michelle Wu and Kim Janey are running for mayor of this state\u2019s capital. Joe Biden nominated a mayor from this state, Marty Walsh, to be Secretary of Labor. A member of the \"Squad,\" Ayanna Pressley, is from this state. Charlie (*) Baker is the governor of this state. The Senate sponsor of the Green New Deal, Ed Markey, was primary challenged by Joe Kennedy III in this state. Elizabeth Warren is a senator from, for 10 points, what state with capital at Boston?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "subcategory": "Current Events", "category": "Current Events", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Massachusetts</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Massachusetts", "Massachusetts"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This artist originally titled one painting for an \u201congoing\u201d concept \u201cstabbed by a dagger.\u201d This artist intended their patron to put one of their works at the base of a staircase to \"stab\" guests ascending it. In a painting by this artist, The Narrative of Arthur Gordon Pym lies to the right of their patron Edward (*) James, who looks forward at the back of his head in a mirror. As well as Not to Be Reproduced, this artist painted two candlesticks and a clock above a train exiting a fireplace. In another work, this artist painted a man in a suit with an apple hiding his face. For 10 points, name this Belgian surrealist who painted Time Transfixed and The Son of Man.", "answer": "Ren\u00e9 Fran\u00e7ois Ghislain Magritte", "subcategory": "Visual Fine Arts", "category": "Fine Arts", "answer_formatted": "Ren\u00e9 Fran\u00e7ois Ghislain <b><u>Magritte</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Ren\u00e9 Fran\u00e7ois Ghislain Magritte", "Magritte"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "One poem named for one of these objects asks the people to \"Rise like lions after slumber / In unvanquishable number,\" and was written by Percy Shelley after the Peterloo Massacre. As well as a Paul Dunbar poem, a Yukio Mishima novel in which Kochan struggles with his homosexuality is titled for one of these objects\u2019 (*) \"Confessions.\" In a story titled for one of these objects, a ball hosted by Prince Prospero is interrupted by a figure wearing one of these objects. That Edgar Allen Poe storyis titled for one of these objects \"of the Red Death.\" For 10 points, name these objects often worn in theater to hide actors\u2019 faces.", "answer": "Masks [or Masque; accept We Wear the Mask, The Masque of Anarchy, Confessions of a Mask, or The Masque of the Red Death]", "subcategory": "World Literature", "category": "Literature", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Masks</u></b> [or <b><u>Masque</u></b>; accept <b><u>We Wear the Mask, The Masque of Anarchy, Confessions of a Mask,</u></b> or <b><u>The Masque of the Red Death</u></b>]", "acceptable": ["Masks", "Masks", "Masque", "We Wear the Mask, The Masque of Anarchy, Confessions of a Mask,", "The Masque of the Red Death"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This scientist's namesake \"surface\" is the space between occupied and unoccupied electron states at zero temperature. According to the Pauli Exclusion Principle, one particle named for this scientist cannot occupy the same quantum numbers. One possible explanation for his namesake paradox is the \"Great Filter.\" This scientist names a type of distribution with Paul Dirac and a particle with (*) half-integer spin that makes up electrons. In the aforementioned paradox, this physicist states that there is a high probability but low evidence for extraterrestrial life. He worked with Leo Szilard (\"sil-lard\") on the Chicago Pile-1 during the Manhattan Project. For 10 points, name this Italian physicist who was the first to conduct a nuclear chain reaction.", "answer": "Enrico Fermi", "subcategory": "Physics", "category": "Science", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Enrico Fermi</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Enrico Fermi", "Enrico Fermi"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "Zephyr Cove lies on the eastern shore of this body of water. A Scandinavian-inspired tea house can be found on Fannette Island in this body of water. Pope and King beaches can be found along the shores of this lake, which has an arm at Emerald Bay. Water from this body of water flows into (*) Pyramid Lake via the Truckee River, its only outflow. Ski resorts such as Squaw Valley and Heavenly Mountain surround this lake, which is near Carson City and Reno. For 10 points, name this alpine lake in the Sierra Nevada mountains, which straddles the border between Nevada and California.", "answer": "Lake Tahoe", "subcategory": "Geography", "category": "Geography", "answer_formatted": "Lake <b><u>Tahoe</u></b>", "acceptable": ["Lake Tahoe", "Tahoe"], "promptable": [], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}, {"question": "This commander tried to escape imprisonment by leaping from a Beaurevoir Castle tower following their capture due to Guillaume de Flavy lifting a drawbridge too soon at Compeigne. Pope Callixtus III authorized a \"nullification trial\" pardoning this commander, who at their original trial replied \"If I am not, may God put me there\" in response to a question about God\u2019s grace. This commander encouraged (*) Charles VII (\"the seventh\") to be crowned at Reims (\"RONCE\"). This commander, who claimed to hear the archangel Michael and Saints Margaret and Catherine, had her most famous victory at Orleans (\"ORE-lee-ON\"). For 10 points, name this French commander during the Hundred Years War, who was burned at the stake for cross-dressing.", "answer": "Joan of Arc [accept Jeanne d\u2019 Arc; prompt on nicknames like the Maid of Orleans]", "subcategory": "European History", "category": "History", "answer_formatted": "<b><u>Joan of Arc</u></b> [accept <b><u>Jeanne d\u2019 Arc</u></b>; prompt on <u>nicknames like the Maid of Orleans</u>]", "acceptable": ["Joan of Arc", "Joan of Arc", "Jeanne d\u2019 Arc"], "promptable": ["nicknames like the Maid of Orleans"], "rejectable": [], "metadata": ""}], "bonuses": []}